Guide to the Stanford University, Center for Research on Women, Female sexuality Project Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Center for Research on Women, female sexuality project records
1973-1991
SC0829
Yalom, Marilyn
3 Linear feet
Questionnaire masters, completed forms, correspondence, reports, and other records from a 1977-78 study of "communication between mothers and college-aged daughters on the subject of sexuality" undertaken by Marilyn Yalom, Suzanne Estler, and Wenda Brewster at Stanford University's Center for Research on Women. Questionnaires were completed by members of the class of 1954 at Stanford University and Wellesley College and by members of the Stanford class of 1980. Collection also includes miscellaneous papers of Yalom including correspondence, photographs, articles, and biographical materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Marilyn Yalom received her BA in French from Wellesley and her MA in German and French from Harvard, completing a PhD in comparative literature at Johns Hopkins, 1963. She has been affiliated with the Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research at Stanford University (formerly the Institute for Research on Women and Gender) since 1976.
Description of the Collection
Questionnaire masters, completed forms, correspondence, reports, and other records from a 1977-78 study of "communication between mothers and college-aged daughters on the subject of sexuality" undertaken by Marilyn Yalom, Suzanne Estler, and Wenda Brewster at Stanford University's Center for Research on Women. Questionnaires were completed by members of the class of 1954 at Stanford University and Wellesley College and by members of the Stanford class of 1980. Collection also includes miscellaneous papers of Yalom including correspondence, photographs, articles, and biographical materials.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Class of 1954.; Stanford University. Class of 1980.; Wellesley College. Class of 1954.; Yalom, Marilyn; Mothers and daughters.; Women --Sexual behavior.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - M. Yalom – Correspondence 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marilyn Yalom: Curriculum Vitae, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Course Evaluation: Marilyn Yalom (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Public Lectures: Marilyn Yalom, 1973-81 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Marilyn Yalom – Newspaper Clippings, 1983-86 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Post-Conference Letters (Poetry Conference), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Government-Corporate-Academia: Linkage Meeting 11/16/84 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - West Coast Women Writers (conference and book), correspondence, 1980-83 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - West Coast Women Writers, correspondence, 1980-84 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Victorian Women – Reviews (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Coming to Light – Reviews (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Coming to Light – Contract U. of Michigan Press (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SWOPSI – Winter 1977 Female Sexuality – Misc. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Related Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - “How Comfortable Are You Talking About Sex?” Questionnaire, completed copies (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Master – Mother Questionnaire (as sent out 7&8/77) to Wellesley and Stanford 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cover Letters (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mother Questionnaire 3/77 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Proposal for Human Subjects Committee (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Human Subjects Panel (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - “Women of the Fifties: Their Past Sexual Experiences and Current Sexual Attitudes in the Context of Mother-Daughter Relationships” [paper] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “Where is the Sexual Revolution? A Study of Mother/Daughter Communication and Generational Change” (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - “What Ought to Be and What Was: Women’s Sexuality in the Nineteenth Century” (by Carl Degler) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “Courses on Women Spring 1978” –prepared by CROW [poster] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SWOPSI Sponsor’s Statement and related papers (includes some duplicates) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Penultimate draft: “Changes in Female Sexuality” (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “Communication on Female Sexuality Between Mothers and College-Age Daughters” (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - “CROW Reports, No.36: Dédoublement in the Fiction of George Sand” (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wellesley Class of 1954 – Roll Call 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Photos and Slides (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Misc. CROW notecards/postcard invites (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Misc. related to female sexuality questionnaires (follow up) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Jing Lyman lectures Fall 1983: Love and Work – “The Challenge for the Family” [poster] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Letter to Marilyn Yalom from Psychology of Women Quarterly, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “Women Writers of the West Coast” book reviews (and related articles) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Articles about Female Sexuality Project study results (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Jessamyn West obituary (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford alums-- #1-15 (plus 2 unnumbered) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford alums-- #16-30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford alums-- #31-45 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford alums-- #46-60 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford alums-- #61-75 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford alums-- #76-93 [end] (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #1-15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #16-30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #31-45 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #46-60 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #61-75 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #76-90 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #91-105 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #106-120 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #121-135 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #136-150 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #151-165 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #166-180 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Stanford Class 1980-- #181-184 (#181 missing) [end] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Wellesley alums-- #1-15 [#2 missing] (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Wellesley alums-- #16-30 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Wellesley alums-- #31-45 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Completed Questionnaires – Wellesley alums-- #46-49 [end] (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Extra packages (blank) – Stanford alums – invites to participate (x4; one packet includes envelope) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Extra blank packages—Stanford alums (x4; incl. sample package and one with envelope) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Extra blank pages – Stanford class 1980 questionnaire – cover, pink sheet, questionnaire (x3) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Extra packages – Wellesley alums (x4) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - “Appendix D” (Box 6, Folder 11)